[Music]
good morning everyone i'm melina program
manager for tensorflow
thank you
welcome to the 2019 tensorflow
developer summit these are a third
annual and largest developer summit two
to date and I'm so happy to have all of
you here both right here in the room and
on the live stream welcome so I'm just
curious by a show of hands who travelled
a little bit further maybe to get here
Europe Asia Africa as far as US
Australia whoa awesome welcome a welcome
to all of you we have a lot of great
talk talks ahead some exciting
announcements and cool demos so let's
get going we are living in a formative
moment of history right now we're
mission where machine learning is
experiencing an unprecedented revolution
though we fundamentally think about and
interact with computer systems hat has
inherently changed due to the
breakthroughs in in the field of AI and
this is due to three major factors first
we have lots more compute specially
designed ml accelerators like like these
teep teep ii use let you train models
faster than ever before
secondly we've breakthroughs in in the
field of machine learning there are
novel algorithms created every month
like a bird and an innovative approach
to natural language processing which
lets anyone around the world train their
own state state-of-the-art
question-answering system and finally we
have lots and lots of data we're seeing
a new we're seeing new waves of data
data sets come from all kinds of
disciplines for example then the new
open images extended data set this is a
collection of over four hundred and
seventy eight thousand images that
volunteers have have added with the
pursuit of a inclusivity and diversity
so all three of these are basically
changing how we solve challenging a
real-world problems and it's really cool
to see that tensorflow is the platform
that's powering this machine learning
revolution it's it's it's allowing
developers businesses and researchers
around the world to benefit from
intelligent applications and we've been
really amazed by what the community has
built with tensorflow
developers have had been using
tensorflow to solve problems in in their
local communities so I don't know if any
of you were in the barrier during the
tragic paradise fire but one of the
consequences was that air quality was
really bad it was in the high to mid to
200 on the air koala
quality index and as difficult as this
was for for us in Delhi India during a
during winter the air quality can get up
to about the the four hundreds on on the
air quality index and this is concerned
very dangerous so pollution sensors can
can help gauge air quality but they're
very expensive to deploy at scale so a
group of students in in Delhi built
image classifiers in tensorflow and and
use those to the built-in building an
app called air cognizer and what it does
is is basically just by using the images
on a smartphone it it gives an accurate
estimation of the air quality businesses
are also fundamentally improving their
products and services built with
tensorflow
for example to a Witter strives to keep
its global users informed with with
relevant and healthy content but this
can be hard when the users follow
hundreds or even thousands of people so
to solve this Twitter launched ranked
timeline animal-powered feed which was
the most relevant tweets at the top of
the time timeline ensuring users never
missed their best and most relevant
content and by using ten servos
ecosystem of tools like tensorflow hub
tensor board and tensor flow model
analysis Twitter was able to reduce both
training and model iteration time
as well as increase the timeline quality
and engagement for users specific
industries are also being very much
transformed by ml G health care for for
example is using tensorflow to improve
MRI imaging these tensorflow models
they're on real-time on MRI scanners and
can actually detect the orientation of
the patient inside the scanner and and
and this is a really great because not
only does this help the diagnosis but
but also lowers the errors and exam time
but also it what's really cool is it
basically expands this technology to
many many more people around the world
tensorflow also powers bleeding-edge
research at a team of scientists
researchers and engineers at nurse Oak
Ridge National Laboratory and an ad
Vidya recently won the Gordon Bell prize
for applying deep learning to to study
the effects of extreme weather patterns
using high-performance computing they
built and scaled a neural network to I
are using tensor flow of course to a run
on Summit their world's fastest
supercomputer they achieved the peak and
sustained throughput of 1.13 exa flops
and FPC 16 which is equivalent to more
than the quantum computations per second
I just think I need to pause for a
second because that is ridiculously fast
right in addition to to these awesome
examples there are thousands and
thousands of people all over the world
doing amazing work using tensor flow and
the power and impact of tensor flow
would not be what it is without all of
you thank you it's it's with your help
and an interest that tentacle has become
the most widely adopted ML framework in
the world and right here I'd like to
show the latest map of github stars who
self-identified their look location I'm
sure many of the dots on this map are
right here in the room and on the live
ships I just want to say thank you one
more time
and this growth has been absolutely
amazing tensorflow has been down
downloaded over 41 million times and has
over 1,800 contributors worldwide
last November we celebrated ten tenths
of a third birthday by taking a look
back at the different components that
that we've added throughout the years
but today we'd like to talk about how
tensorflow has matured as a platform to
become an entire end-to-end ecosystem
and tensorflow 2.0 is the start of a new
era and we're committed and focused on
making it the best ml platform for all
our users so talk more about tensorflow
to tirado I'd like to introduce Raja
manga engineering director of tensor
flow on stage thank you Thank You Lena
hello everyone
I'm Raja I am an engineer intensive
floor and have been involved with this
since the very beginning it's been great
to see what we've been up to over the
last few years all the amazing growth
and all the amazing things that you've
done with it
it's also been great to hear from you
that's what you like about tensile foam
and equally importantly what you would
like to see improved in terms of your
feedbacks been loud and clear you asked
for simpler more intuitive api's and
development experiences you pointed out
areas of redundancy and complexity and
you asked for better documentation and
examples
and this is exactly what we've been
focusing on with turns flow 2.0
to make it easy we focused on Keros for
a single set of api's and combine it
with eager execution for the simplicity
of python its ex ability to try the
craziest ideas inability to go beyond an
exaflop tensorflow is more powerful than
ever
with the same robustness and performance
you expect in production battle-tested
and Google
let's start with the overall
architecture for tensorflow
you may be familiar with this high-level
architecture they've been lots of
components and features we've added
throughout the years to help support
workloads to go from training to
deployment intensive flow 2.0 we're
really making sure that these components
work better together
here's how these powerful API components
fit together for the entire training
work for the TF data for data ingestion
and transformation
caris and pre-made estimators from model
building training with eager execution
and graphs and finally packaging for
deployment would save money
let's take a look at some examples the
first thing you need is data often you
may want to validate results or test
your new ideas or in common public data
set tensorflow data sets includes a
large in rapidly growing collection of
public data sets that you can get
started with very easily and combined
with TF data it is simple to wrap your
own narrative
here's a small sample of the data sets
that are available and all of these and
many more are included there
then with Karis you can express the
model with layers just as you are used
to thinking about it standard training
and evaluation is packaged as well with
model fit and evaluate
since steep learning models are often
computationally expensive you may wanna
try scaling this across more than one
device tensorflow comes pre-built with
mirrored strategy that works with small
additions to your code
starting from a pre-trained modular
component also works well to reduce some
of this computational cost to make it
easy
tensorflow hub provides a large
collection of pre trained components
that you can include in your model and
even find you in for your specific data
set
Kerris an estimator offer high-level
building blocks for an easy-to-use
package they come with everything you
might need for typical training jobs
but sometimes you need a bit more
control for example when you're
exploring new kinds of algorithms
let's say you wanted to build a custom
encoder for machine translation here's
how you might do this by sub-classing a
model here you can focus on implementing
the computational algorithm and let the
framework take care of the rest and you
could even customize the training loop
to get full control over the gradients
and the optimization process
while training models rather package
with carers or more complex ones it's
often valuable to understand the
progress and even analyze the model in
detail tensor board provides a lot of
visualization to help with this
and now it comes full integration with
inter collab and other jupiter notebooks
allowing you to see the same
visualizations right from within your
notebook
all of these features are available in
tensorflow 2.0
and I'm really excited to announce that
our alpha release is available for you
as of today many of you in the room and
across the world really helped with lots
of work in testing to make this possible
I really think they'd like to take this
moment to thank you all please give
yourself a round of applause we really
couldn't have done this without you
[Applause]
in addition to all the great
improvements we talked about this
release comes with a converter script to
help you upgrade from one point X and a
compatibility module to give you access
to the one point X API is for easy
transition
working towards the full release over
the next quarter
there's a lot of work going on to make
tensorflow 2.0 it really work well for
you you can track the progress and
provide feedback on the tents of locate
hub projects page
you asked for better documentation and
we work to streamline our docks four
api's guides and tutorials
all of this material will be available
today on the newly redesigned tensorflow
door org website we'll find more
examples documentation and tools to get
started we're really very excited about
these changes and what's to come
and to tell you more about improvements
intensive flow for research and
production I'd like to welcome Megan
Cachola on stage thank you thanks Rajat
tensorflow has always been a platform
for research to production we just saw
how tensorflow as high-level api's make
it easy to get started and build your
models now let's talk about how it
improves powerful experimentation for
researchers unless you take models from
research and prototyping all the way
through to production
researchers have been using tensorflow
for state-of-the-art research we can see
it in paper publications which are shown
over the past few years in this chart
but powerful experimentation begins and
really needs flexibility this begins
with easy eager execution with tensor
flow and tensor flow 2.0 by default
every Python command is immediately
executed this means you can write your
code and the style you're used to
without having to use such and run this
also makes a big difference in the realm
of debugging
as you iterate through with eager mode
you'll eventually want to distribute
your code on two GPUs GPUs and other
hardware or accelerators for this we've
provided TF function which turns your
eager code into a graph function by
function you get all of the familiar
tools like Python control flow asserts
even print but can convert to a graph
anytime you need to including when
you're ready to move your model into
production and even with us you'll
continue to get great debugging debug
ability is great not just in eager but
we've made huge improvements in TF
function and graphs as well and this
example shown here we're splitting a
tensor using TF function which creates a
graph but because of the mismatched
inputs you get an error as you can see
we now give users the information about
the file and the line number where the
error occurred in the model to help you
more quickly track things down so you
can continue iterating we've made the
error messages concise easy to
understand and actionable we hope you
enjoy these changes and they make it
much easier for you to quickly iterate
and progress with your models
performance is another area we know that
researchers as well as all users for
that matter care about and we've
continued improving core performance and
tensor flow since last year we've sped
up training on eight nvidia tesla v1
hundreds by almost double using a google
cloud TPU v2 we've boosted performance
by 1.6 x and with Intel MKL acceleration
we've got an inference speed up by
almost three times performance we'll
continue to be a big focus of tensor
flow 2.0 and a core part of our progress
to final release
tensorflow also provides flexibility to
enable researchers and this is with many
add-on libraries that extend and expand
tensor flow in new and useful ways some
of these add-on libraries or extensions
to make certain problems easier like TF
text with Unicode and the new ragged
tensor type in other cases it lets us
explore how we can make machine learning
models fairer and safer by OTF privacy
you'll also hear new announcements on TF
agents for reinforcement learning and
tomorrow we'll be discussing the new TF
federated library for federated learning
deep loading research is also being
applied to real-world applications using
tensor flow here are a few examples from
researchers at Google where we see them
applying it areas like our data centers
we're making them more efficient with a
I control system that delivers energy
savings our apps like Google Maps the
one shown in the middle which has a new
navigation feature called global
localization it combines visual
positioning service Street View and
machine learning to more accurately
identify position and orientation and
devices like the Google pixel that use
machine learning to improve depth
estimation to create better portrait
mode photos like the one shown here
in order to make these real-world
applications a reality you must be able
to take models from research and
prototyping all the way through to
launching in production this has always
been a core strength and focus for
tensor flow using tensor flow you can
deploy your models on a number of
platforms like shown here and models end
up in a lot of places so we want to make
sure tensor flow works well across all
of these on servers and in cloud on
mobile and other edge devices in browser
and JavaScript platforms we have
products for each of these tensor flow
extended tons of flow light and tensor
flow Jas which I'll briefly talk through
tensorflow extended is our indian
platform for managing every stage of the
machine learning lifecycle this spans
all the way from ingesting and
transforming your data to deploying your
machine learning models at scale in
orange
she don't shown here you can see the
libraries we've open-sourced so far what
this slide alludes to is that we're now
taking a step further and providing
components built from these libraries
that make up an end-to-end platform and
note these are the same components that
are used internally in thousands of
production systems powering Google's
most important products the components
are only part of the story 2019 is the
year we're putting it all together and
providing you with an integrated into
end platform first you can bring your
own Orchestrator here we're showing air
flow or coop flow or even raw kubernetes
whatever you want no matter what
Orchestrator you choose the tensor flow
extending components integrate with a
metadata store this store keeps track of
all the component runs the artifacts
that went into him into them and the
artifacts that were also produced this
enables advanced features like
experiments experimentation and
experiment tracking model comparison and
things along those lines that I'm sure
you'll be excited about and will help
you as you iterate through and work with
your production systems we have an end
and talk coming up later today from
Clements and his team in which they'll
take you on a complete tour of using
tensor flow extended to solve a real
problem
moving on tensorflow light is our
solution for running models on mobile
and IOT hardware it uses a custom stream
line file format and a stripped-down
runtime so you can deploy tensorflow
models everywhere your users are on
device models can be more responsive to
input than cloud backends and they keep
user data on device for privacy which is
very important especially in this day
and age Google and our partners like hae
in China use TF Lite for all kinds of
tools including predictive text
generation video segmentation and things
like edge detection
but under the hood tensorflow light is
about performance you can deploy models
to CPU GPU and even edge CPUs and expect
fast performance and we've been refining
since we launched tensorflow light last
year by using the latest quantization
techniques on CPU adding support for
OpenGL 3.1 and metal on GPUs and tuning
our performance on edge CPUs we're
constantly pushing the limits of what is
possible on device and you should even
greater enhancements in the year ahead
we'll hear details from Raziel and his
colleagues coming up in a little bit
this morning
javascript is the number one programming
language in the world until recently
hasn't necessarily benefited from all
the machine learning development and
tools last year we released tensorflow
Jas a library for training and deploying
machine learning models in the browser
and on nodejs since then we've seen huge
adoption in the JavaScript community
with more than 300,000 downloads and 100
contributors but we're just at the
beginning given how big the JavaScript
and web ecosystem is today we're excited
to announce tensorflow J's version 1.0
this comes with many improvements and
new features we have a library of
off-the-shelf models for common machine
learning problems that run both in the
browser and on node we're also adding
support for more platforms where
JavaScript runs such as electron desktop
apps or mobile native platforms and a
huge focus in tensorflow gjs 1.0 is on
performance improvements as an example
compared to last year mobile net
inference and browser is now 9 times
faster you'll learn more about these
advances in our talk later in the day
another language that we're really
excited about is swift swift for
tensorflow is reexamining what it means
for performance and usability with a new
stack built on top of ten circles core
and a new programming model that it
intends to bring further usability and
today we're announcing that Swift for
tensorflow is now at version 0.2 it's
ready for you to experiment with to try
out and we're really excited to be
bringing this to the community in
addition to telling you about version
0.2 we're also excited to announce that
Jeremy Howard a fast a I is writing a
new course in Swift for tensorflow Chris
and Brennan will tell you a lot more
about this later today
so to recap everything we've shown you
so far tensorflow has grown to a full
ecosystem from research to production
from sir berlin to mobile with many
languages this growth has been fueled by
our community and honestly would not
have been possible without the community
to talk about what we're planning for
you and with you in 2019 I'll hand it
over to come on Thank You Megan hi my
name is Kemal and I'm the product
director for tensorflow I'm really
excited to be here today for this
celebration and what we're celebrating
is the most important part of what we're
building and that's the community
personally I love building developer
platforms I used to be a developer as an
entrepreneur and now I get to enable
other developers by building together a
better platform
when we started working on 2.0 we turned
to the community we started with the
request for common process consulting
with all of you on important product
decisions we received valuable feedback
and we can have built 2.0 without you
and some of you wanted to get more
involved so we created special interest
groups or cigs like networking or tensor
war to name a few and cigs are really a
great way for the community to build the
pieces of tensorflow that they care the
most about we also wanted to hear more
about what you were building so we
launched it powered by tensorflow
campaign and I gotta say we were amazed
by the creativity of the project from
biological image analysis to custom
wearables to chat BOTS so after three
years our community's really thriving
there almost 70 machine learning GT
e--'s right now around the world
eighteen hundred contributors on core
alone and countless more of you who are
doing amazing work to help make
tensorflow successful so on behalf of
the whole tensorflow team we want to say
a huge thank you so we have big plans
for 2019 and I would like to make a few
announcements first as our community
grows we welcome people who are new to
machine learning and it's really
important to provide them with the best
educational material so we're excited to
announce
two new online courses one is with deep
learning da di and it's published in the
Coursera platform and the others with
Udacity the first batch of these lessons
is available is available right now and
they provide an awesome introduction to
tensorflow for developers they require
no prior knowledge to machine learning
so I highly encourage you to check them
out next if your students for the very
first time you can apply to the google
Summer of Code program and get to work
with the tensorflow engineering team to
help build a part of tensorflow
talked about the powered by tensorflow
campaign were so excited with the
creativity that we decided to launch a
2.0 hackathon on death post to let you
share your latest and greatest and win
cool prizes so really excited to see
what you're going to build
finally as our ecosystem grows we're now
having a second day at the summit but we
really wanted to do something more we
wanted a place where you can share what
you've been building on tensorflow so
we're excited to announce
since of the world a week-long
conference dedicated to open source
collaboration this conference will be Co
presented by aurélie media and
tensorflow
and will be held in Santa Clara and of
October our vision is to bring together
the Austin tensorflow world and give a
place for folks to connect with each
other so I'd like to invite on stage
Geena blader to say a few words about
the conference Thank You Camille
O'Reilly is a learning company with a
focus on technology and business we have
strong ties with the open source
community as many of you know and we
have a history of bringing big ideas to
life that's why we're excited about
partnering with tensorflow
to create this new event that brings
machine learning and AI to the community
the event is tensorflow happening
October 28 to 31 in Santa Clara and when
I say community I mean everyone we want
to bring together the entire tensorflow
community of individuals and teams and
enterprises this is the place where
you'll meet experts from around the
world the team that actually creates
tensorflow
and the companies and enterprises that
will help you deploy it we have an open
CFP right now on the tensorflow world
site I invite you all to check that out
and send in your proposal soon so your
voice is heard at that event we look
forward to seeing you at tensorflow
world in october thank you
[Applause]
Thank You Gina this is gonna be great
are you guys excited whoo so we have a
few calls to action for you take a
course submit a talk to TF world start
hacking into point oh by the way the
grand prize is for a hackathon on DEF
post will include free tickets to
tensorflow world you know a one thing I
love is to hear about these amazing
stories of people building awesome stuff
on top of tensorflow
and as a team we really believe that AI
advances faster when people have access
to our tools and can then apply them to
the problems that they care about in
ways that we never really dreamed of and
people when people can really do that
some special things happen and I'd like
to share with you something really
special
consult our documentary sobre todo
document in medieval a dia de sempre
molto Tampa Malta Batsy Anza yenakiyevo
Takano
abbiamo Santosh in kilometres in area
document pure men all along gates at the
canal de Panama descriptor a discreet
nelma do avo sono diverse edevalla
denomination sake we're committed a
sound or not the transcriber a trade or
to t documented LF gia vaticano super
elementary dragoon motto looking at this
book page by page and trying to decipher
grid and transcribe whatever is there
takes an enormous amount of time she
would require an army of paleography
what i'm excited the most about smashing
learning i said it enabled us to solve
problems that up to ten fifteen years
ago without unsolvable in karate not
requested any costly a software
purported interpret our brutality Lucas
kita dendrimers critic Wanda brem
initiated approach re problem attrition
Orissa Kentucky knows will turn a
possibility no rally for say as
Reutimann Tanisha's Aria la shelter zoo
tensorflow esta vez and Sarah to rally
before using any kind of machine
learning model we needed to collect data
first you have thousands of images of
dogs and cats in the internet but it's
very little images of ancient
manuscripts we build our own custom web
application for crowdsourcing and we
involved high school students to collect
the data I didn't know much about
machine learning in general but I found
it very easy to create a tensorflow
environment when we were trying to
figure out which model work best for us
caris was the best solution the
production model runs on tons of flow
layers and estimator interface we
experimented with binary classification
fully connected networks and finally we
move to convolutional neural network and
multi-class classification in poco
tiempo say malucia tia as VIP artists
are le premiers of its own when it comes
to recognizing single characters we can
get 95% average accuracy
Patera cheddar most amento format ago
abre via medieval meant Salieri shared
abbreviation comprende room Tesco in
Quilici to Ragosa Kritika uncle cosas de
traditionally this will have an enormous
impact in a short period of time we will
have a massive quantity of historical
information available I just think
solving problems is fun it's a game
against myself and how good I can do law
studio de la storia important isom /
comprende knows represent a para ver en
que una perspectiva very food or oh this
is this is such a great story I think
about the scholars who wrote these
manuscripts you could imagine they could
have been imagined that centuries later
people will be using computers to bring
back to life their work so we're really
lucky to have Elena with us today lino
would you stand
don't miss the talk where she will share
her story today I'm I really hope you
have a great day we have some really
awesome things the team and I there will
be around please come and say hi we want
to hear from you and with that I'm gonna
hand it over to Martin who will talk
about tensorflow 2.0 thank you
[Music]